Guide to the North Star Mining Company and Associated Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize, 17.5
  - SERIES VIII. NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
    - Financial Records
      - Analyzed statements
        - Monthly analyzed statements of disbursements - Paper documents, 1894-96 (Box 110, Folder 2352-55)
        - Monthly analyzed statements of disbursements - Paper documents, 1896-98 (Box 111, Folder 2355A-57)
        - Monthly analyzed statements of disbursements - Paper documents, 1899 (Box 112, Folder 2358)
      - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1893 Nov (Box 112, Folder 2358A)
      - Monthly tribute statements, 1897-1902 (Box 112, Folder 2359-64)
      - Monthly tribute statements, 1903-04 (Box 113, Folder 2365-66)
  - SERIES XI. OTHER MINING COMPANIES AND ASSOCIATIONS
    - Idaho - Maryland Quartz Mine
      - Map (Box 113, Folder 2367)
    - Original Empire Mill and Mining Company
      - Insurance policy, 1896 Feb (Box 113, Folder 2368)
    - Unidentified Mining Companies
      - Operation records - Maps of Grass Valley - Nevada City mining claims, 1930, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2369)
      - Other material - Photoprints--Mine buildings (albumen), 1892 (Box 113, Folder 2370)
  - SERIES VII. PRINTED MATERIAL
    - "1860--Pony Express Centennial--1960." Virginia City Times (Virginia City, Nevada) (Box 113, Folder 2371)
    - American Gold News (San Andreas, California), 1961 (Box 113, Folder 2372)
  - SERIES III. GOLD HILL MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Special projects and reports - Pump sketches, [1897] (Box 114, Folder 2373)
    - Financial Records
      - Trial balances, 1896-97 (Box 114, Folder 2374)
  - SERIES IV. GRANITE HILL MINING & DEVELOPMENT CO.
    - Executive Records
      - Insurance Policy, 1899 Nov 6 (Box 114, Folder 2375)
  - SERIES V. GRASS VALLEY WATER COMPANY
    - Financial Records
      - Paid drafts, vouchers, receipts, 1886 (Box 114, Folder 2376)
  - SERIES VI. MASSACHUSETTS HILL MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes - Certificate of incorporation, 1888 Oct 11 (Box 115, Folder 2377)
  - SERIES VIII. NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Correspondence - Received at Grass Valley, 1904 May 25 (Box 115, Folder 2378)
    - Operation Records
      - Monthly mining reports, 1887-91 (Box 115, Folder 2379-83)
      - Monthly mining reports, 1892-97 (Box 116, Folder 2384-89)
      - Monthly mining reports, 1898-1901 (Box 117, Folder 2390-93)
      - Monthly mining reports, 1902-05 (Box 118, Folder 2394-97)
      - Maps of North Star properties and mines, ca. 1914 (Box 119, Folder 2398)
    - Financial Records
      - Analyzed statements - Summaries, 1890-91 (Box 119, Folder 2399)
      - Monthly tribute statements, 1897 (Box 119, Folder 2400)
  - SERIES XI. OTHER MINING COMPANIES AND ASSOCIATIONS
    - Twin River Consolidated Mining Company (Nevada)
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1873 Jul 5 (Box 119, Folder 2401)
    - Unidentified Mining Records
      - Operation Records - Mines samples and mapped by Joy, 1931-32 (Box 119, Folder 2402)
      - Operation Records - Map of Grass Valley - Nevada City mining claims and mills, 1867 (Box 119, Folder 2403)
  - SERIES VII. PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Grass Valley Daily Union, 1890 (Box bsd, folder 2404)
    - Drama of the Comstock by Paul Smith (Virginia City, Nevada), 1949 (Box bsd, folder 2405)
    - The Arizona Republic, 1953 Jun 28 (Box bsd, folder 2406)
    - The Union (Grass Valley - Nevada City, California), 1954; 1962 (Box bsd, folder 2407–bsd, folder 2408)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 3.25
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 4-5 (Box 120, Folder 2409-10)
  - Box 1, folder 14 (Box 120, Folder 2411)
  - Box 1, folder 27 (Box 120, Folder 2412)
  - Box 2, folders 30-31 (Box 120, Folder 2413-14)
  - Box 3, folders 50-51 (Box 120, Folder 2415-16)
  - Box 6, folder 107 (Box 120, Folder 2417)
  - Box 8, folders 164-66 (Box 120, Folder 2418-20)
  - Box 8, folders 170-73 (Box 120, Folder 2421-24)
  - Box 8, folders 175-76 (Box 120, Folder 2425-26)
  - Box 8, folders 178-79 (Box 120, Folder 2427-28)
  - Box 8, folders 183-84 (Box 120, Folder 2429-30)
  - Box 8, folders 186-89 (Box 120, Folder 2431-34)
  - Box 10, folders 214-15 (Box 120, Folder 2435-36)
  - Box 10, folder 217 (Box 120, Folder 2437)
  - Box 10, folder 228 (Box 120, Folder 2438)
  - Box 10, folder 238 (Box 120, Folder 2439)
  - Box 11, folder 269 (Box 120, Folder 2440)
  - Box 11, folders 270-71 (Box 120, Folder 2441-42)
  - Box 12, folder 289 (Box 120, Folder 2443)
  - Box 12, folder 290 (Box 120, Folder 2444)
  - Box 20, folder 467 (Box 120, Folder 2445)
  - Box 20, folders 486-87 (Box 120, Folder 2446-47)
  - Box 21, folder 510 (Box 120, Folder 2448)
  - Box 22, folder 518 (Box 120, Folder 2449)
  - Box 24, folder 584 (Box 120, Folder 2450)
  - Box 27, folder 702 (Box 120, Folder 2451)
  - Box 28, folder 735 (Box 120, Folder 2452)
  - Box 30, folder 739 (Box 120, Folder 2453)
  - Box 30, folder 740 (Box 120, Folder 2454)
  - Box 30, folder 746 (Box 120, Folder 2455)
  - Box 30-31, folders 748-61 (Box 120, Folder 2456-69)
  - Box 31, folder 767 (Box 120, Folder 2470)
  - Box 31, folder 769 (Box 120, Folder 2471)
  - Box 32, folder 772 (Box 120, Folder 2472)
  - Box 32, folder 778-80 (Box 120, Folder 2473-75)
  - Box 34, folder 797-98 (Box 120, Folder 2476-77)
  - Box 34-37, folders 799-844 (Box 121, Folder 2478-2523)
  - Box 37-39, folders 845-863 (Box 122, Folder 2524-42)
  - Box 39, folders 865-68 (Box 122, Folder 2543-46)
  - Box 39-40, folders 874-75 (Box 122, Folder 2547-48)
  - Box 40, folder 878 (Box 122, Folder 2549)
  - Box 40, folders 880-83 (Box 122, Folder 2550-53)
  - Box 40, folders 885-90 (Box 122, Folder 2554-59)
  - Box 41, folders 893-97 (Box 122, Folder 2560-64)
  - Box 41, folder 899 (Box 122, Folder 2565)
  - Box 41, folder 901 (Box 122, Folder 2566)
  - Box 41, folder 903 (Box 122, Folder 2567)
  - Box 41, folder 906 (Box 122, Folder 2568)
  - Box 42, folders 908-12 (Box 122, Folder 2569-73)
  - Box 42, folders 915-16 (Box 122, Folder 2574-75)
  - Box 42, folders 918-22 (Box 122, Folder 2576-80)
  - Box 53, folder 1240 (Box 122, Folder 2581)
  - Box 80, folder 1896 (Box 122, Folder 2582)
  - Box 90, folder 1897 (Box 122, Folder 2583)
  - Box 90, folder 1900 (Box 122, Folder 2584)
  - Box 90, folder 1914 (Box 122, Folder 2585)
  - Box 90, folder 1923 (Box 122, Folder 2586)
  - Box 90, folder 1947 (Box 122, Folder 2587)
  - Box 93, folder 2112 (Box 122, Folder 2588)
  - Box 93, folder 2110 (Box 123, Folder 2489)
  - Box 119, folder 2400 (Box 123, Folder 2590)
  - Box 113, folder 2371 (Box 123, Folder 2591)
  - Box 113, folder 2372 (Box 123, Folder 2592)
  - Broadside folders 2404-2408 (Box 124, Folder 2593-97)